http://www.landscapeinstitute.org/privacy-policy

Landscape apprenticeships
The Future State of Landscape: Education and practice review
Landscape apprenticeships
The Future State of Landscape: Education and practice review
Purpose of this privacy notice
This privacy notice outlines how we may use information that we obtain about you when you visit our websites (www.landscapeinstitute.org, campus.landscapeinstitute.org, awards.landscapeinstitute.org, www.chooselandscape.org), do business with us as a member or customer of the LANDSCAPE INSTITUTE, act as an adviser to our members or customers, act as a supplier to the LANDSCAPE INSTITUTE or other contact or as the officer, employee or other person related to such entities or apply for a job with us.
Our websites are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.
It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you, so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.
Controller
The LANDSCAPE INSTITUTE is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “the Institute”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).
We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below.
Contact details
Our full details are:
Full name of legal entity: the Landcape Institute
Name of data privacy manager: Andy Wallace
Email address: contact@landscapeinstitute.org
Postal address: Landscape Institute, 85 Tottenham Court Road, London W1T 4TQ
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes
It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
Third-party links
Our websites may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our websites, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
The data we collect about you
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).
We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:
Identity Data includes first name and last name.
Contact Data includes your email address, telephone number and business address.
Professional Data includes your job title and company name.
Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our website.
Usage Data includes information about how you use our website and services.
Marketing and Communications Data includes information that allows us to choose how best to market specific communications to you.
Special Categories of Personal Data where you provide this to us in the context of your instructions or in applying for a job (this may include details about your race or ethnicity, religious beliefs, sexual orientation and information about your health).
We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.
If you fail to provide personal data
Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you or your employer and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into (for example, to provide the goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel the contract but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.
How is your personal data collected?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
Direct interactions. You may give us your data through our provision of services or goods to you, your employer or the organisation you represent, during the course of dealings with you for or on behalf of a client, and by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by website, post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
apply for or use our goods and/ or services;
subscribe to our service or publications;
request marketing to be sent to you; or
give us some feedback.
Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns.
Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:
Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU.
Identity and Contact Data from publicly available sources such as the internet, Experian, Companies House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.
How we use your personal data
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
To carry out services we have agreed to provide to you.
You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.
Purposes for which we will use your personal data
We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
.Purpose/ Activity
Type of data
Lawful basis for processing including legitimate interest to do so
To register you as a new member or customer
Identity
Contact
Performance of a contract
To manage payments, fees and charges and collect any fees owed to us
Identity
Contact
Financial Information
Marketing and Communications
Performance of a contract
Our legitimate interests to recover and process debts due to us
To provide services and manage our relationship with you including using a third party to assist in the provision of the services
To include providing you with information you request, satisfaction surveys, changes to our services/ products or this privacy notice.
Identity
Contact
Professional
Marketing and Communications
Performance of a contract
Our legitimate interests to provide the services you require, keep you updated and receive feedback
Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, data handling and reporting)
Identity
Contact
Usage
Professional
Our legitimate interests to run our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud or prevent access to the data we hold
Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and to measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
Identity
Contact
Usage
Marketing and Communications
Technical
Our legitimate interests to run our business, keep our website and marketing relevant and updated, develop our business and inform our marketing strategy
To respond to any job applications we receive
Identity
Contact
Professional
Special Categories
Our legitimate interest to develop and grow our business and inform our recruitment strategy
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about services/ products that may be of interest to you
Identity
Contact
Technical
Usage
Consent
Our legitimate interest to develop and grow our business
Marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:
Promotional offers from us
We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, and Usage Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).
You may receive marketing communications from us if you have purchased services from us previously and you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
Opting out
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at any time.
Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a service purchase or other transactions.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
Disclosures of your personal data
We may have to share your personal data with the third parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.
Service providers acting as processors based in the UK who provide services to us, including but not limited to, IT.
Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers who provide services to us.
HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
Third party service providers who provide services that involve data processing, translation, technology, research, banking and payment, client contact, data entry and processing, litigation support, marketing and security services and other similar services.
Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
International transfers
Some of our external third parties may be based or may send personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data may involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.
Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:
Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.
Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.
Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.
Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
Data retention
How long will you use my personal data for?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
By law we have to keep basic information about our clients (including Contact, Identity, and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being clients for regulatory purposes.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
Your legal rights
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.
You have the right to:
Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.
No fee usually required
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
What we may need from you
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
Time limit to respond
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
Cookies
Cookies are text files stored on your computer, and accessible only to the websites which create them.
Our website may from time to time use cookies and log files for statistical analysis, to understand user behaviour, to administer the site, to tailor the information presented to a user based on their preferences, and to improve user experience. Any information gathered by our use of cookies is compiled on an aggregate, anonymous basis.
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, however you may delete, or disable cookies by following the instructions at http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/. Please note that you may not be able to take full advantage of a website if you disable cookies.
Further information about cookies can be found on the Interactive Advertising Bureau’s website www.allaboutcookies.org.
Service
Cookie
More Information
Privacy / Opt Out
Google Analytics
“_utm*”
Analytics software enables usage statistic tracking such as entrance and exit points, bounce rates, conversion and related events.
http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/
Facebook
act, locale, lu, datr, csm
Allow interaction with social and share buttons such as “Like”
https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy
Twitter
guest_ID, secure_token_session
Allow interaction with social and share buttons such as “Tweet”
https://twitter.com/en/privacy
Application Insights
ai_user and ai_session: Microsoft Azure Application Insights
Microsoft App Insights is used to collect telemetry and understand what users do on our site and report issues, errors and bugs.
https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/application-insights/app-insights-data-retention-privacy
Eventbrite
Ordering, track and target interests and enhance analytics and advertising.
https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/support/articles/en_US/Troubleshooting/eventbrite-cookie-policy?lg=en_GB
YouTube
“_utm*”
Tracking, content recommendations, analytics and advertising
https://www.youtube.com/static?gl=GB&template=terms
Log Files
Our systems automatically gather some anonymous information about visitors, including IP addresses, browser type, language, and the times and dates of webpage visits. The data collected does not include personally identifiable information and is used, as described above, for statistical analysis, to understand user behaviour, and to administer the site.
Google Analytics
Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Further information about Google’s privacy policy may be obtained from http://www.google.com/privacy.html.
Application Insights
We’re collecting various telemetry items through Microsoft’s Application Insights telemetry scripts, like “timings of page loads, requests, calls, counts and details of browser exceptions and AJAX failures, as well as users and session counts. All these can be segmented by page, client OS and browser version, geo location, and other dimensions”. To understand better how application insights collects and stores data please visit https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/application-insights/app-insights-data-retention-privacy
Glossary
LAWFUL BASIS
Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service and the best and most secure experience particularly in compliance with our agreed terms and conditions with you (in the case of clients of the LANDCAPE INSTITUTE), or agreed terms of business (in the case of suppliers to the LANDCAPE INSTITUTE). We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.
Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.
Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
85 Tottenham Court Road
London W1T 4TQ
0330 808 2230
Charity registered in England and Wales Number 1073396
Charity registered in Scotland number SC047057Contact us: contact@landscapeinstitute.org
© Copyright Landscape Institute 2018 | Privacy Policy
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.Ok
